A Finding Aid to the Trudy Sween Papers, 1966-1982, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Trudy Sween papers
1966-1982
Archives of American Art
Sween, Trudy
AAA.sweetrud
Archival Resource Key
0.5 Linear feet
The papers of painter, poet, and sculptor Trudy Sween measure 0.5 linear feet and date from 1966 to 1982. Found are biographical materials, correspondence, designs for logos and medals, and printed material.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. Access to original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center.
Scope and Contents
The papers of painter, poet, and sculptor Trudy Sween measure 0.5 linear feet and date from 1966 to 1982. Found are biographical materials, correspondence, designs for logos and medals, and printed material.
Existence and Location of Copies
The collection is available on 35mm microfilm reel 3274 at Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the material described in the container inventory does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm.
Biographical / Historical
Trudy Sween (1929-2017) was known primarily as a painter, but was also a sculptor and a published poet based in Houston, Texas.
Sween studied at the University of Houston and often exhibited her works in Texas. She was a founder of the Cultural Arts Council of Houston and served on its executive board for many years.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Trudy Sween donated portions of her papers to the Archives of American Art in 1982-1983.
Arrangement
Due to the small size of this collection the papers are arranged as one series.
Painters -- Texas -- Houston; Women artists; Women painters; Sculptors -- Texas -- Houston; Poets -- Texas -- Houston; Women sculptors
- Trudy Sween Papers, 1966-1982; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 1, OV 2
  Scope and Contents
  Biographical materials consist of artist statements, a resume, and four transparencies of works of art. Scattered correspondence includes letters from various arts organizations in Houston, Texas. Sween's designs are for logos, seals, and medals, and are hand-drawn and also includes a prototype. Sween designed items for the City of Houston, Jones College, and Rice University. The bulk of the collection consists of printed materials including a book of poems accompanied by artwork entitled Innerscapes, clippings, exhibition announcements, catalogs, and posters.
  - Biographical Material, 1967-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Designs, circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Printed Material, Innerscapes, by Trudy Sween, 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Printed Material, Clippings, 1966-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Printed Material, Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Printed Material, Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Printed Material, Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1980-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Printed Material, Posters, Oversized, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 2)